Guide to the Frederick H. Smyth Collection of Fire Photographs 1899-1926 (Bulk 1908-1914) PR 63
New-York Historical Society
Frederick H. Smyth Collection of Fire Photographs
1899-1926 (Bulk 1908-1914)
New-York Historical Society
PR 63
7 Linear feet (13 boxes)
The collection includes photograph albums and glass plate negatives of New York City fires, firefighters, fire engines and firefighting equipment.
Provenance
Gift of Robert E. Logan in 1958.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Biographical Note
Frederick Hugh Smyth (1878-1949) made a hobby of taking and collecting photographs of New York City fires. Smyth retired as the bursar of the American Museum of Natural History in 1942 after working there from the age of 14. Smyth was a member of the New York Firemen Cycle Club. He was living in South Orange, NJ at the time of his death.
Scope and Content Note
The Frederick H. Smyth Collection of Fire Photographs spans the period from 1899 to 1926 and primarily contains photographs of the New York City Fire Department at work. The collection provides an invaluable look at firefighting technology and equipment in New York at the beginning of the twentieth century. Images record the transition from horse-drawn fire wagons to motorized engines. In addition, the collection shows many individual fires, including the famous Triangle Shirtwaist Fire of 1911 and the 1912 fire at the Equitable Building. The collection is divided into two series: Albums; and Negatives.
Series I. Albums consists of two disbound photograph albums together containing a total of 378 prints. Each album page measures 10 by 14 inches and holds between one and four prints. Each image was assigned a unique number by Smyth, and described by him on the verso of the page. The numbers correspond to the negatives in Series II, but the prints are not arranged by number in the albums. Many of the photos taken of fires in winter show large ice formations on buildings and fire equipment. These were generally noted as "ice-coated" by Smyth in the image title.
Album 1 spans the period from 1899-1925 and consists mainly of images of fires and fireboats. Notable fires include the National Biscuit Company fire in 1906, Windsor Hotel fire in 1899, the Equitable Building Fire in 1912, Lipton Tea Warehouse in 1909, Triangle Shirtwaist Fire in 1911, Delaware Lackawanna Ferry in 1909, the Casino Theatre in 1925, and the ruins of the 1911 fire at the Dreamland amusement park at Coney Island. Other blazes pictured include: a piano factory on West 49th street, a loft building on Mercer Street, a paper warehouse on Lafayette Street, a pier, a tenement, an oil warehouse, a shanty, a subway explosion, a wallpaper factory, and other locations in Manhattan, Brooklyn, and the Bronx. The album concludes with many pages of fireboats, particularly those named "Thomas Willett," "New Yorker," and "W. J. Gaynor," some photos taken while the boats were in action.
Album 2 includes similar types of photos from 1904 to 1926 but also incorporates copy photographs of lithographs (most by Currier and Ives) depicting early fires in New York City. Some other copy photography, taken by photographers other than Smyth, is included here along with Smyth's original images. These photographers are noted on the versos of the album pages as: Van Altena, Mr. Phillips, Mr. Henry, and I. Dutcher. Most pictures in this album are of firefighting equipment, portraits of firefighters, parades or award ceremonies, equipment drills, and interior and exterior views of firehouses. Fire Chiefs and Commissioners shown include John Binns, John Kenlon, Edward Croker, Rhinelander Waldo, and Joseph Johnson.
Series II. Negatives includes 405 negatives. Fifty of these are film, the remainder are glass, primarily 5 x 7 inches. Smyth numbered each in the emulsion. The negatives are filed numerically and, as mentioned above, this order does not correspond to the page numbering system in the albums of prints. Thirty images are glass transparencies or autochromes, and therefore do not have corresponding prints in Series I. These are interfiled numerically with the negatives. Please refer to the item-level list following this finding aid, or the database, to see titles of negatives without prints.
When the negatives came to the New-York Historical Society, they were assigned a prefix of 61055 and were housed in the Negative File. All vintage negatives have now been removed from the Negative file. Negative sleeves still show this prefix, but negatives are only referred to by Smyth's numbers in this finding aid.
A database was created to record the album and page number, image number, image title, and address and date in order to facilitate the use of the collection. Printouts of this database follow the finding aid. These lists are sorted by album and page number; by borough and address; and by image (negative) number. The database is also searchable by keyword for subjects.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series.
Missing Title
Series I. Albums
Series II. Negatives
Transparencies; negatives (photographs); Glass negatives.; Historic buildings -- New York (State).; Autochromes; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Manhattan (New York, N.Y.); Fires -- New York (State); Horse-drawn vehicles; Fire engines; Photograph albums.; Fire extinction -- Equipment and supplies; Wagons; Horseshoeing; Fireboats; Fire extinction -- Equipment and supplies -- Inspection; Fires -- New York (State) -- New York.; Fire departments -- Officials and employees; Fire fighters -- Training of.; New York (N.Y.); Photographic prints.; Equitable Building (New York, N.Y.); Triangle Shirtwaist Company
- Series I: Albums
  Scope and Contents note
  The series consists of two disbound photograph albums together containing a total of 378 prints. Each album page measures 10 by 14 inches and holds between one and four prints. Each image was assigned a unique number by Smyth, and described by him on the verso of the page. The numbers correspond to the negatives in Series II, but the prints are not arranged by number in the albums.
  Titles in the finding aid are based on, but not exact transcriptions of, the descriptions provided by Smyth.
  - Album 1, pages 1 - 153, 1899-1925 (Offsite-box 1)
  - Gansevoort Street High-Pressure Pumping Station, exterior, Gansevoort & West Streets (Negative 244658) (Page 1)
  - High-pressure fire hydrant (Negative 244659) (Page 1)
  - Piano Factory Fire, West 49th Street (Negative 244660), 1909 (Page 1)
  - Piano Factory Fire, fireboats being used, West 49th Street (Negative 244661), 1909 (Page 1)
  - Piano Factory Fire, West 49th Street (Negatives 244662-244665), 1909 (Page 3)
  - Piano Factory Fire, West 49th Street (Negatives 244666-244669), 1909 (Page 5)
  - Piano Factory Fire, engines working, West 49th Street (Negative 244670), 1909 (Page 7)
  - Factory Fire, West Broadway (Negative 244671-244673) (Page 7)
  - Factory Fire, West Broadway (Negatives 244674-244675) (Page 9)
  - Loft Building Fire, Mercer Street (Negatives 244676-244677), [1913] (Page 9)
  - Loft Building Fire, Mercer Street (Negatives 244678-244680), [1913] (Page 11)
  - Paper Warehouse Fire, Lafayette & White Streets (Negative 244681), 1912 (Page 11)
  - Paper Warehouse Fire, Lafayette & White Streets (Negatives 244682-244684), 1912 (Page 13)
  - Hay Wagon Fire (Negative 244685) (Page 13)
  - Hay Wagon Fire (Negative 244686) (Page 15)
  - Pier Fire, Rector Street (Negative 244687-244688), 1910 (Page 15)
  - Apartment House Fire, 57th Street and 9th Avenue (Negative 244689), 1909 (Page 15)
  - Ruins, National Biscuit Company Fire, East Side (Negative 244691), [1906] (Page 17)
  - Factory Fire (Negative 244690) (Page 17)
  - Tenement House Fire, East Side (Negative 244692), 1908 (Page 17)
  - Factory Fire, [541] West 34th Street (Negative 244693), [1909] (Page 17)
  - Showing Firehose (Negative 263066) (Page 19)
  - Lumber Fire, West 29th Street (Negative 263067) (Page 19)
  - Oil fire, deck stream from water, South Street (Negative 263068) (Page 19)
  - Firehose Wagon No. 58 (Negative 263069) (Page 19)
  - Fenced shanty, Election Day (Negative 263062) (Page 21)
  - Extension ladder used at fire (Negative 263063) (Page 21)
  - Windsor Hotel Fire, rescuers at work, 571 Fifth Avenue (Negative 263064), 1899 (Page 21)
  - High pressure test, West Street (Negative 263065), 1910 (Page 21)
  - Shanty Fire (Negatives 244694-244696) (Page 23)
  - Factory Fire, Mott Street (Negative 244697), 1912 (Page 23)
  - Factory Fire, Mott Street (Negatives 244698-244700), 1912 (Page 25)
  - Factory Fire, Mott Street (Negative 244701), 1912 (Page 27)
  - [Factory Fire] Fighting fire from upper floors and roofs, East 57th Street (Negative 244702), 1915 (Page 27)
  - Factory Fire, East 57th Street (Negative 244703), 1915 (Page 29)
  - Factory Fire, West 25th Street (Negative 244704), 1920 (Page 29)
  - Fire Engine pumping, Broome Street and Broadway (Negative 244705), 1904 (Page 29)
  - Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negative 244706), 1912 (Page 29)
  - Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negatives 244707-244708), 1912 (Page 31)
  - Fire in rubbish pile, 107th Street & Riverside Drive (Negative 244709) (Page 31)
  - Cellar Fire (Negative 244710), 1912 (Page 31)
  - Cellar Fire (Negative 244711), 1912 (Page 33)
  - Fire Engine pumping (Negative 244712), 1914 (Page 33)
  - Oil Fire, taken from ferry boat, Jersey City (Negative 244713), 1911 (Page 33)
  - Oil Fire, Jersey City (Negative 244714), 1911 (Page 33)
  - Windsor Hotel Fire, 571 Fifth Avenue (Negative 410588-410589), 1899 (Page 35)
  - Windsor Hotel Fire, 571 Fifth Avenue (Negative 410590), 1899 (Page 37)
  - Ruins, car barns, West 42nd Street and 12th Avenue (Negative 410591), 1905 (Page 37)
  - Interior telegraph room (Negative 410586), 1905 (Page 39)
  - Windsor Hotel Fire, 571 Fifth Avenue (Negative 410587), 1899 (Page 39)
  - Warehouse Fire, firemen taking up lines (Negative 263060) (Page 41)
  - Earle Warehouse Fire, South Street (Negative 263061) (Page 41)
  - Garbage Fire, West 96th Street (Negative 106252), 1911 (Page 43)
  - Oil Warehouse Fire, Water Street. Chief Walsh (in white hat) later killed in Equitable Building Fire (Negative 106253), 1911 (Page 43)
  - Oil Warehouse Fire, firemen with lines, Water Street (Negative 106254), 1911 (Page 45)
  - Oil Warehouse Fire, Water Street (Negative 106255), 1911 (Page 45)
  - Oil Warehouse Fire, fire engines at work, Water Street (Negative 106256), 1911 (Page 47)
  - Warehouse Fire, East 129th Street & Third Avenue (Negative 106257) (Page 47)
  - Warehouse Fire, East 129th Street & Third Avenue (Negative 106258-106259) (Page 49)
  - Lipton Tea Warehouse Fire, No. 27 High Pressure Wagon, ice-coated, 96 Hudson Street (Negative 106260-106261), 1909 (Page 51)
  - Lipton Tea Warehouse Fire, ruins, 96 Hudson Street (Negatives 106262-106263), 1909 (Page 53)
  - Loft Building Fire, Broadway & Houston Street (Negatives 106264-106265), 1912 (Page 55)
  - Loft Building Fire, Broadway & Houston Street (Negatives 106266-106267), 1912 (Page 57)
  - Loft Building Fire, 11th Street & Broadway (Negatives 106268-106269) (Page 59)
  - Loft Building Fire, 11th Street & Broadway (Negatives 106270-106271) (Page 61)
  - Loft Building Fire, 11th Street & Broadway (Negatives 106272-106273) (Page 63)
  - Loft Building Fire, 11th Street & Broadway, from University Place (Negatives 106274-106275) (Page 65)
  - Loft Building Fire, 11th Street & Broadway (Negative 106276) (Page 67)
  - Loft Building Fire, strong stream of water from tower, 11th Street & Broadway (Negative 106277) (Page 67)
  - Loft Building Fire, four lines connected to high pressure hydrant, 11th Street & Broadway (Negative 106278) (Page 69)
  - Loft Building Fire, water tower at work, 11th Street & Broadway (Negative 106279) (Page 69)
  - Equitable Building Fire, as it started, 120 Broadway (Negatives 106280-106281), 1912 (Page 71)
  - Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negatives 106283-106284), 1912 (Page 73)
  - Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negative 106284), 1912 (Page 75)
  - Equitable Building Fire, ice-coated facade, 120 Broadway (Negative 106285), 1912 (Page 75)
  - Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negatives 106286-106287), 1912 (Page 77)
  - Equitable Building Fire, Engine No. 13 ice-coated, 120 Broadway (Negative 106288), 1912 (Page 79)
  - Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negative 106289), 1912 (Page 79)
  - Fire Chief John Kenlon at the Equitable Building Fire, 120 Broadway (Negatives 106290-106291), 1912 (Page 81)
  - Triangle Waist Co. Factory Fire, Washington Place & Greene Street (Negative 106292-106293), 1911 (Page 83)
  - Triangle Waist Co. Factory Fire, Washington Place and Greene Street (Negatives 106294-106295), 1911 (Page 85)
  - Triangle Waist Co. Factory Fire, Washington Place & Greene Street (Negative 106296-106297), 1911 (Page 87)
  - 3rd Alarm Fire, West 67th Street & West End Avenue (Negative 106298), 1913 (Page 89)
  - 3rd Alarm Fire, Engine No. 39, West 67th Street & West End Avenue (Negative 106299), 1913 (Page 89)
  - Bronx Fire, East 149th Street & Third Avenue (Negative 106301), 1912 [1911] (Page 91)
  - Fire Commissioner Rhinelander Waldo at Bronx Fire, East 149th Street & Third Avenue (Negative 106302), 1912 [1911] (Page 92)
  - Bronx Fire, rescue scene, East 149th Street & Third Avenue, (Negative 106303), 1912 (Page 92)
  - Bronx Fire, East 149th Street & Third Avenue, (Negatives 106304-106305), 1912 [1911] (Page 93)
  - Bronx Fire, Fire Commissioner Rhinelander Waldo and his secretary Winfield Sheehan, 149th Street & Third Avenue. (Negatives 106306-106307), 1911 (Page 95)
  - Bronx Factory Fire, Fire Commissioner Rhinelander Waldo and Deputy Fire Commissioner Joseph Johnson, 149th Street & Third Avenue (Negative 106308), 1911 (Page 97)
  - Bronx Department Store Fire, East 132nd Street & Third Avenue, (Negative 106309) (Page 97)
  - Express Building Fire, Searchlight Engine at work, 11th Street & Seventh Avenue, (Negative 106310-106311) (Page 99)
  - Express Building Fire, Searchlight Engine at work, 11th Street & Seventh Avenue (Negative 106312) (Page 101)
  - Building Fire, Wooster Street, (Negative 106313) (Page 101)
  - Building Fire, water towers and roof stream, Wooster Street (Negative 106314) (Page 103)
  - Fire engines at work, West 43rd Street near Eleventh Avenue (Negative 106315) (Page 103)
  - Fire engines at work, West 43rd Street near Eleventh Avenue (Negative 106316) (Page 105)
  - Garage Fire, auto-pumping engine, West 69th Street & West End Avenue (Negative 106317) (Page 105)
  - Fire, smoke from engine, Water Street (Negative 106318), 1911 (Page 107)
  - Delaware Lackawanna Ferry Fire (Negative 106319), 1909 (Page 107)
  - 5th Alarm Fire, Wallpaper Factory, West 34th Street & Eleventh Avenue (Negative 106320), 1909 (Page 109)
  - Ruins of Dreamland, Coney Island (Negative 106321), 1911 (Page 109)
  - Ruins of Dreamland, Coney Island (Negative 106322), 1911 (Page 111)
  - Ruins, Brooklyn Fire (Negative 106323) (Page 111)
  - Burned Mail Wagons (Negative 106324), 1914 (Page 113)
  - Dangerous condition of fire escapes (Negative 106325), 1912 (Page 113)
  - Oil Fire, Jersey City (Negatives 244715-244717), 1911 (Page 115)
  - Fire Department officials at explosion, West 23rd Street & Broadway (Negative 244718), 1914 (Page 115)
  - Explosion, West 23rd Street & Broadway (Negative 244719-244722), 1914 (Page 117)
  - City officials at explosion, West 23rd Street & Broadway (Negative 244723), 1914 (Page 119)
  - Subway cave-in, West 24th Street & Seventh Avenue (Negatives 244724-244725), 1913 (Page 119)
  - Fireboats (Negative 244726) (Page 119)
  - Casino Theater Fire (Negative 254839)Casino Theater Fire (Negative 254839), 1925 [?] (Page 121)
  - Boys building a fire in the street, Election Night (Negative 254840), 1925 [?] (Page 121)
  - Traffic policeman clearing traffic, 1410 Broadway (Negative 254841), 1925 [?] (Page 121)
  - Launching Fireboat "W.J. Gaynor" (Negatives 106228-106229), 1912 (Page 123)
  - Launching Fireboat "W.J. Gaynor" (Negatives 106230-106231), 1912 (Page 125)
  - Fireboat "Thomas Willett" (Negatives 106232-106233), 1913 (Page 127)
  - Fireboat "Thomas Willett" (Negatives 106234-106235), 1913 (Page 129)
  - Fireboat "Thomas Willett" test of streams (Negatives 106236-106237), 1913 (Page 131)
  - Fireboat "Thomas Willett" (Negative 106238), 1913 (Page 133)
  - Auxiliary Fireboat "Velox" for use of Fire Chief (Negative 106239), 1913 (Page 133)
  - Fireboats in action off the Battery (Negatives 106240-106241), 1913 (Page 135)
  - Fireboats in action off the Battery (Negatives 106242-106243), 1913 (Page 137)
  - Fireboats off the Battery (Negatives 106244-106245), 1913 (Page 139)
  - Fireboats in action (Negative 106248) (Page 143)
  - Fireboats at Garbage Fire, West 96th Street Pier (Negative 106249), 1914 (Page 143)
  - Fireboats at Garbage Fire, West 96th Street Pier (Negative 106250-106251), 1914 (Page 145)
  - Test on NY Times Building, West 41st Street & Broadway (Negative 410592), 1908 (Page 147)
  - Fireboat "New Yorker", interior pilot house (Negative 410593), 1909 (Page 147)
  - Fire Chief John Kenlon and water turret of fireboat "New Yorker" (Negative 410594-410595), 1909 (Page 149)
  - Fire Chief John Kenlon and water turret of fireboat "New Yorker" (Negative 410596), 1909 (Page 151)
  - Fireboat "New Yorker" in action (Negative 410597-410598), 1908-1909 (Page 153)
  - Album 2, pages 1 - 179, 1904-1926 (Offsite-box 2)
  - Copy of a lithograph depicting the Volunteer Fire Department, 'The American Fireman, Facing the Enemy" (Negative 410558) (Page 1)
  - Copy of a lithograph depicting the Volunteer Fire Department fighting the Barnum's Museum Fire (Negative 410559) (Page 1)
  - Copy of a lithograph depicting the Volunteer Fire Department on the way to a fire (Negatives 410560-410561) (Page 3)
  - Copy of a lithograph depicting the Volunteer Fire Department (Negative 410562) (Page 5)
  - Copy of a lithograph depicting the Volunteer Fire Department, engine passing Worth Monument at Madison Square (Negative 410563) (Page 5)
  - Mayor William J. Gaynor inspecting new automotive fire apparatus [engine] (Negative 106107), 1913 (Page 7)
  - Mayor William J. Gaynor and Fire Commissioner Joseph Johnson inspecting new fire alarm box at City Hall (Negative 106108), 1913 (Page 7)
  - Mayor William J. Gaynor turning in a fire alarm at City Hall (Negative 106109), 1911 (Page 9)
  - Fire alarm box (Negatives 106110-106111), 1911 (Page 11)
  - Fire alarm signal box, interior (Negatives 106112-106113), 1911 (Page 13)
  - Fire alarm signal box, interior (Negative 106114), 1911 (Page 15)
  - Fire Chief John Kenlon (Negatives 106121-106122), 1912 (Page 17)
  - Fire Chief John Kenlon (Negatives 106123-106124), 1912 (Page 19)
  - Dr. Harry M. Archer, Honorary Deputy Fire Chief (Negatives 106125-106126) (Page 21)
  - Deputy Fire Chief John Binns, in car with driver, at 100 Duane Street, Engine Company 7 (Negatives 106127-106128), 1906 (Page 23)
  - Deputy Fire Chief John Binns, in car with driver, at 100 Duane Street, Engine Company 7 (Negative 106129), 1906 (Page 25)
  - Copy of a lithograph depicting the Volunteer Fire Department (Negative 410564) (Page 27)
  - Deputy FIre Chief John Binns, in car with driver, at 205 West 77th Street, Hook and Ladder 25 (Negative 410567), [1906] (Page 27, Page 29)
  - Deputy Fire Chief John Binns in car with unidentified fireman (Negative 410566), 1906 (Page 29)
  - Deputy Fire Chief John Binns, in car with unidentified fireman, at 205 West 77th Street, Hook and Ladder Company 25 (Negative 410567), 1907 (Page 29)
  - Fire Chief Edward F. Croker and opera singer Madam Nellie Melba inspecting a firehouse at West 43rd Street (Negative 410570), [1910] (Page 33)
  - Firemen wearing their medals (Negative 410571), 1904 (Page 33)
  - 4th of July Parade, Chief Edward F. Croker riding in car with other Fire Department officials, Fifth Avenue between 14th and 15th Streets. (Negative 106150), 1910 (Page 35)
  - 4th of July Parade, led by Cavalry, Fifth Avenue between 14th and 15th Streets (Negative 106151), 1910 (Page 35)
  - 4th of July Parade, Searchlight Engine and Engine 26, Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106153), 1910 (Page 37)
  - 4th of July Parade, Searchlight Engine and Engine 26, Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106154), 1910 (Page 37, Page 39)
  - 4th of July Parade, Engine Company with High Pressure Wagon, Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106155), 1910 (Page 39)
  - 4th of July Parade, Engine Company, High Pressure Wagon Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106156), 1910 (Page 41)
  - 4th of July Parade, Hook & Ladder Company, High Pressure Wagon, Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106157), 1910 (Page 41)
  - 4th of July Parade, Hook & Ladder Company, Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106158), 1910 (Page 43)
  - 4th of July Parade, Water Tower Company, Fifth Avenue between 14th & 15th Streets (Negative 106159), 1910 (Page 43)
  - Volunteer Firefighters on float in Hudson-Fulton Parade (Negatives 244634-244636), 1909 (Page 45)
  - Fire Chief Edward F. Croker and firemen at an East Side fire (Negative 244637), 1909 (Page 45)
  - Spanish American War Veterans of the Fire Department, at West 76th Street near Riverside Drive (Negative 106130), 1912 (Page 47)
  - Army & Navy men of the Fire Department, at West 76th Street near Riverside Drive (Negative 106131), 1912 (Page 47)
  - Fire Department Women's Auxiliary Club group portrait (Negative 106132) (Page 49)
  - Firemen being honored with medals at City Hall (Negatives 106133-106134), March 20, 1913 (Page 51)
  - Firemen being honored with medals at City Hall (Negative 106135), March 20, 1913 (Page 53)
  - Firemen being honored with medals at City Hall (Negative 106136), 1913 (Page 55)
  - Firemen lined up in formation, West 86th Street & Riverside Drive (Negative 106137), 1913 (Page 55)
  - Fire Department parade, horse and wagon (Negative 106138) (Page 57)
  - Fire Department medal ceremony with the Mayor, West 86th Street & Riverside Drive (Page 57)
  - Fire Department medal ceremony with the Mayor, West 86th Street & Riverside Drive (Negative 106140) (Page 59)
  - Fire Department medal ceremony with the Mayor, West 86th Street & Riverside Drive (Negative 106141) (Page 59)
  - Fire Department medal ceremony with the Mayor, Union Square (Negative 106142), 1916 (Page 61)
  - Fire Department horse and wagon, Union Square (Negative 106143), 1916 (Page 61)
  - Fire Department Drill, Van Cortlandt Park, Bronx (Negative 106144-106145), 1913 (Page 63)
  - Fire Department Drill, Van Cortlandt Park, Bronx (Negatives 106146-106147), 1913 (Page 65)
  - Fire Department Drill, Van Cortlandt Park, Bronx (Negatives 106148-106149), 1913 (Page 67)
  - Battalion Chief on way to a fire in horse-drawn carriage (Negatives 244638-244639) (Page 69)
  - Probationary firemen with scaling ladders, 157 East 67th Street (Negatives 244640-244641), 1910 (Page 69)
  - Probationary firemen with scaling ladder, 157 East 67th Street (Negative 244642), 1910 (Page 71)
  - Surgeons at work [police and firemen at an excavation site] (Negative 244643) (Page 71)
  - Rescue Company fire engine (Negative 244644) (Page 71)
  - Firemen honored with medals (Negative 244645), 1912 (Page 71)
  - Mayor John P. Mitchel throwing out ball at FDNY-NYPD baseball game (Negative 244646), 1912 [1914] (Page 73)
  - Auto Fire Engine, Engine Company 58 (Negatives 244647-244648), 1911 (Page 73)
  - Hook & Ladder Company 26 on way to a fire, Madison Avenue & East 114th Street (Negative 244649), 1906 (Page 73)